<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog.atom"/>
  <title>Kodiak Sports, LLC - Kodiak Sports Blog</title>
  <updated>2017-08-17T11:04:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Kodiak Sports, LLC</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/kodiak-helps-launch-extreme-studio-performance-in-dallas-tx</id>
    <published>2017-08-17T11:04:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-25T18:29:33-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/kodiak-helps-launch-extreme-studio-performance-in-dallas-tx"/>
    <title>Kodiak Helps Launch Extreme Studio Performance in Dallas, TX</title>
    <author>
      <name>Matt Garrabrants</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3>Rubber Flooring &amp; Speed/Agility Turf</h3>
<p>Extreme Studio Performance - By Kodiak Sports 2017</p>
<p>The project used Kodiak Commercial Grade <a href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/collections/rubber-flooring/product_rolled-rubber-flooring" title="Rubber Flooring Rolls">Rolled Rubber Flooring</a> for the fitness equipment area and the Kodiak Hybrid <a href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/collections/artificial-turf" title="Artificial Sports Turf">Sports Turf</a> with inlaid white lines and hash marks to give it the ultimate performance look and feel.<br><br>The project totaled around 7000 sq. ft. of sports turf and 3/8" thick rubber flooring.</p>
<p>"Mike was a pleasure to work with and together we were able to build him an amazing facility." - Kodiak Sports<br><br>The floor was sanded and cleaned prior to the rubber installation to give the flooring the ultimate bond and eliminate any bumps and problems in the surface.<br><br>The customer selected a Gray rubber flooring color fleck to give it some color and keep it looking fresh. Thanks to Mike and his partners for trusting Kodiak Sports to do a great job for you!<br><br>Kodiak supplies rubber floors, wall padding, sports turf and pole padding nationwide as well as performing nationwide installation.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/kodiak-sports-completes-on-deck-sports-pro-batting-cage-in-athens-tx</id>
    <published>2015-02-03T10:57:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-25T18:30:01-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/kodiak-sports-completes-on-deck-sports-pro-batting-cage-in-athens-tx"/>
    <title>Kodiak Sports Completes On Deck Sports Pro Batting Cage in Athens, TX</title>
    <author>
      <name>Amy White</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>January 20th, 2015 Kodiak Sports has completed a new batting cage in the town of Athens, TX named On Deck Sports Pro. </p>
<p>The new batting cage includes 3 iron mike pitching machines with coin operated token boxes as well as timed rentals administered through a computerized digital central control panel. Flat floor turf facilities are popular due to the lower cost of materials in comparison to a sloped floor/automated ball collection system.  In addition, flat floor areas are able to be used for other activities including short toss, flips, soft toss and general batting practice.  Sloped floor cages are generally dedicated space that can not be re-purposed at different times of day when the needs of the clients and faculties can vary depending on the customer base and time of year.</p>
<p><strong>Equipment:</strong> The facility was outfitted with Kodiak Sports Netting, Jr. Collegiate Sports Turf with foam pad, 5' x 8' Kodiak Pro Mini L-Screens, Nylon Hitting Mats, and Kodiak Pro Aluminum Ball Carts. Kodiak Sports manufacturers, supplies and installs everything you need for your commercial batting cage and sports training facility. 877-401-2298 - Toll Free <a title="Request a Quote" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/s.nl/it.I/id.18/.f?sc=21&amp;category=-121" target="_blank">Request a Quote</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/murray-state-university-rubber-flooring</id>
    <published>2015-02-03T10:47:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-25T18:29:29-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/murray-state-university-rubber-flooring"/>
    <title>Murray State University Rubber Flooring</title>
    <author>
      <name>Amy White</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>Murray State Rolled Rubber Flooring Fitness Center</strong> Murray State has performed a weight room flooring renovation using Kodiak Commercial Grade Rolled Rubber Flooring.  The project totaled just under 7000 sq. ft. of 3/8" thick rubber flooring.</p>
<p>The project required the removal of existing flooring and weight room equipment to way for the new glue down rolled rubber flooring.  Patching and repairing any damaged areas of concrete was required prior to installing the new flooring. Murray State selected a yellow speckle on the floor; giving the room a great color contract of yellow on black.</p>
<p>Kodiak Sports Performs Nationwide <a title="Buy Rubber Flooring" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/RUBBER-FLOORING" target="_blank">Rubber Flooring</a> Installations and product sales. </p>
<p>Purchase orders accepted and professional expertise is just a phone call away!</p>
<p>877-401-2298 - Toll Free <a title="Request a Quote" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/s.nl/it.I/id.18/.f?sc=21&amp;category=-121" target="_blank">Request a Quote</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/should-you-glue-down-your-rolled-rubber-flooring</id>
    <published>2015-01-07T18:42:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-25T18:30:07-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/should-you-glue-down-your-rolled-rubber-flooring"/>
    <title>Should you glue down your rolled rubber flooring?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Amy White</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>Yes - you should...but will you?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Gluing Rolled Rubber Flooring</strong> - <strong>The Basics:</strong> Understanding how rolled rubber is made is an important aspect of understanding when to glue the rubber down. Recycled rolled rubber flooring is made by mixing particles of rubber with a urethane binder (glue).  Which means the rubber is NOT melted down or solid; like many people think. Rolled rubber has air pockets trapped in between the rubber and bind.  These air pockets allow air/moisture to have an effect on the rubber flooring...similar to how moisture can expand and buckle a wood floor.  Areas of high humidity or hydrostatic pressure under the concrete/wood floor/sub-base can allow moisture to affect the rubber floor. This moisture can buckle and wrinkle your rolled rubber floor.</p>
<p><strong>What does the glue do to help with moisture problems?</strong> Good quality moisture cured urethane adhesives have moisture barrier technology included in the glue.  This moisture barrier seals the concrete/wood substrate against moisture passing through and into your rubber floor.</p>
<p><strong>Is taping down my rolled rubber going to work?</strong> Double sided carpet tape is not the manufacturer recommended method of installation.  HOWEVER, many users choose to tape the floor to avoid the cost and permanent installation of a glue down installation. Generally, double sided tape installations will perform well in dry climates and on substrates that are sealed against moisture. If you have concrete or substrate with a moisture problem; you should seal the substrate prior to laying the rolled rubber flooring.  Then you can likely install your rolls without the moisture causing buckling and wrinkling. However, if you drag equipment or roll equipment across the floor...it may shift or wrinkle forcing you to relay it over and over.</p>
<p>Ultimately, you are taking responsibility for installing the rubber flooring incorrectly when you use tape.  But there are certain precautions to maximize your chances of success.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/texas-rubber-mulch-free-shipping</id>
    <published>2014-05-08T23:56:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-25T18:29:43-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/texas-rubber-mulch-free-shipping"/>
    <title>Texas Rubber Mulch - Free Shipping</title>
    <author>
      <name>Amy White</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong>Rubber Mulch for Texas Playgrounds, Backyards and Landscaping</strong> Kodiak has <a title="Rubber Mulch" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/rubber-mulch">rubber mulch</a> for playgrounds, landscaping and other applications in Texas and can ship within 48 hours. <strong>Product Highlights:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Best Quality in Industry</li>
<li>Fast 24-48 hour shipping</li>
<li>Free shipping to Texas</li>
<li>12 Year Color Stay Life</li>
<li>Color Will not transfer to skin or clothes</li>
<li>ASTM F1292-09 Certification for fall heights up to 16 feet high</li>
<li>Wheelchair accessible per ASTM F1951-99</li>
</ul>
<p>We have 4 rubber mulch colors in stock in Texas at all Times. Black, Cedar Red, Blue and Green We have the best color technology with urethane colors (not water based paint) so the brilliant color won't rub off on clothing or transfer.</p>
<p>Rubber Mulch in Texas with Free shipping</p>
<p>Call Kodiak - 877-401-2298 - Toll Free</p>
<p>Houston, San Antonio, Dallas, Austin, Fort Worth, El Paso, Arlington, Corpus Christi, Plano, Laredo, Lubbock, Garland, Irving, Amarillo, Grand Prairie, Brownsville, Pasadena, Mesquite, McKinney, McAllen, Killeen, Waco, Carrollton, Frisco, Beaumont, Abilene,, Denton, Midland, Round Rock, Wichita Falls, Odessa, Richardson, Lewisville, Tyler, College Station, San Angelo, Pearland, Allen, League City, Sugar Land, Longview, Mission,, Edinburg, Bryan, Baytown, Pharr, Missouri City, Temple, Flower Mound, Harlingen, North Richland Hills, Victoria, New Braunfels, Conroe, Mansfield, Rowlett, Port, Arthur, Euless, Cedar Park, DeSoto, Georgetown, Pflugerville, Galveston, Bedford, Grapevine, San Marcos, Cedar Hill, Texas City, Haltom City, Wylie, Keller, Coppell,, Duncanville, Rockwall, Sherman, Huntsville, Hurst, The Colony, Burleson, Lancaster,, Weslaco, Texarkana, Friendswood, Del Rio, Lufkin, San Juan, La Porte, Nacogdoches, Socorro, Deer Park, Copperas Cove, Schertz, Rosenberg, Waxahachie, Cleburne, Kyle,, Farmers Branch, Leander, Lake Jackson, Big Spring</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/rubber-mulch-for-playgrounds-5-colors</id>
    <published>2014-05-08T23:25:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-28T09:17:24-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/rubber-mulch-for-playgrounds-5-colors"/>
    <title>Rubber Mulch for Playgrounds - 5 Colors</title>
    <author>
      <name>Amy White</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>Rubber Playground Mulch Colors and Color Quality</strong></p>
<p><a title="Rubber Mulch for Playgrounds" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/RUBBER-MULCH">Rubber mulch</a> comes of a variety of colors for playgrounds, landscaping and obstacle courses. Kodiak rubber mulch comes with a 12 year color safe warranty; the longest in the industry.  Our rubber mulch will not transfer to clothing like our competitors rubber mulch; we use urethane color coatings vs competitors water based paint. Rubber mulch provides safety from fall heights up to 16' high in compliance with ASTM F1292-09 certified standards.</p>
<p><strong>Mulch:</strong> Rubber mulch is available in 1000lb and 2000lb bags. Coverage will vary by thickness of the area for fall heights.</p>
<p>Contact Kodiak at 877-401-2298 - Toll Free <a title="Kodiak Sports" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com">http://www.kodiaksports.com</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/cross-fit-rubber-flooring-quality</id>
    <published>2014-04-17T12:50:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T18:31:28-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/cross-fit-rubber-flooring-quality"/>
    <title>Cross Fit Rubber Flooring Quality</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong>CrossFit and 4' x 6' x 3/4" Rubber Floor Tiles</strong>
<strong>Problem Overview:</strong>
Many of our <a title="CrossFit Rubber Flooring" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/RUBBER-FLOORING/Cross-Fit-Flooring" target="_blank">CrossFit Floooring</a> customers struggle with understanding the different grades and qualities of <a title="Rubber Flooring" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/RUBBER-FLOORING/Cross-Fit-Flooring" target="_blank">rubber flooring</a> tiles on the market.
Many Crossfit customers tend gravitate to the least expensive animal grade matting from the local tractor/farm supply; only to find these cheap rubber mats dangerous; hard to clean, absorb blood, sweat, moisture, harbor staph and other dangerous bacteria within the pores and chip/break down easily under heavy/repeated impact.
[caption id="attachment_129" align="alignnone" width="300"]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/rubber_tile_cheap.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-129" alt="rubber mats" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_rubber_tile_cheap-300x253.jpg?12440910922171447715" width="300" height="253"></a> Urethane/Glued Animal Grade Mats[/caption]
<strong>Solution:</strong> Commercial Grade Vulcanized CrossFit Flooring
Now that you have seen what the low grade animal rubber flooring looks like and understand that it's just particles of rubber glued together...let's talk about the proper flooring for a commercial gym.
Vulcanized Rubber Flooring is MELTED solid.  Kodiak Flooring produces rubber mats/sheet goods by using crumb rubber; deodorizing agents and other additives for proper bonding to create solid rubber mats.  A vulcanized mat is imperious to water, blood, sweat, moisture, staph and other bacteria.  Once you clean the surface, there is no place for the foreign substances to absorb into the mat.
See the difference in the vulcanized rubber shown below?  Note the lack of open pores, gaps, rough surface?
[caption id="attachment_130" align="alignnone" width="300"]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/diamond_straight.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-130" alt="Vulcanized Diamond Plate Tiles" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_diamond_straight-300x290.jpg?4742855293131690514" width="300" height="290"></a> Kodiak Vulcanized Diamond Plate Tiles[/caption]
[caption id="attachment_131" align="alignnone" width="300"]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/premium_green_detail_zoom.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-131" alt="Kodiak Hammerlock Vulcanized Rubber Tiles" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_premium_green_detail_zoom-300x300.jpg?15068615129872725275" width="300" height="300"></a> Kodiak Hammerlock Vulcanized Rubber Tiles[/caption]
Contact Kodiak Sports today to have a sales specialist help you select the rubber flooring that will meet your budget and perform to give you a real return on investment.<strong>
</strong>
 
 ]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/getting-more-color-in-your-rubber-gym-flooring</id>
    <published>2014-03-21T16:49:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T18:30:10-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/getting-more-color-in-your-rubber-gym-flooring"/>
    <title>Getting More Color in your Rubber Gym Flooring</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong>Rubber Flooring Color Flake</strong>
So you don't want a regular black rubber floor?
[caption id="attachment_125" align="alignnone" width="213"]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/Photo009_zoom.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-125" alt="Blue Rubber" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_Photo009_zoom-300x164.jpg?735756178122410025" width="213" height="116"></a> Add Amazing Color with Kodiak Color Blend Technology![/caption]
Kodiak rubber flooring is used from the New Yorker Hotel to the Statue of Liberty to 1000's of schools and gyms across the nation.  Most facilities use a black or black with color speckle to keep costs down.  The fitness center below is a small business trying to make a profit; so budget is the most important factor.
[caption id="attachment_118" align="alignnone" width="300"]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/rockcity_crossfit2.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-118" alt="cross fit flooring" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_rockcity_crossfit2-300x199.jpg?6374024264778870109" width="300" height="199"></a> Solid Black Rubber in a Cross Fit Gym[/caption]
We all know rubber flooring is functional and durable; but sometimes it's not about function over form.  Sometimes you want a brilliant floor that makes your room standout and it's worth spending the extra money to make it pop.
If you are living a fairly healthy lifestyle; you spend a lot of time in your gym and fitness room..maybe between 1 - 2 hours per day.  Why not make it the beautiful room you want it to be?
[caption id="attachment_117" align="alignnone" width="641"]<a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_Photo111_thumb.jpg?3475406340557855512"><img class=" wp-image-117" alt="Color Rubber" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_Photo111_thumb.jpg?3475406340557855512" width="641" height="96"></a> 90% Color Rubber Flooring Rolls and Tiles[/caption]
How do we get such brilliant color into a recycled rubber floor?
Kodiak mixes virgin EPDM rubber granules with our black recycled rubber flooring particles to create custom colors in solids and blended mixes.
This process does significantly increase the cost of the rubber flooring; the most color, the higher the cost!  But that is the price of beauty!
Check out the <a title="Rubber Floor Pricing" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/RUBBER-FLOORING/Rolled-Rubber-Flooring" target="_blank">Rubber Flooring</a> page to view prices.]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/vinyl-garage-flooring-or-rubber-flooring</id>
    <published>2014-03-21T16:36:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T18:28:51-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/vinyl-garage-flooring-or-rubber-flooring"/>
    <title>Vinyl Garage Flooring or Rubber Flooring?</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong>Garage Flooring - How to Pick the Right Floor for the Job</strong>
Garage Flooring is often confused with <a title="Rubber Weight Room Flooring" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/Rubber-Flooring" target="_blank">rubber flooring</a> that is used in weight rooms, gyms, and fitness centers.  It is important to understand the composition and differences so that you can make a proper choice for your application.
<strong>Garage Flooring Characteristics:</strong>
<ul>
	<li>Made of Poly Vinyl (not rubber)</li>
	<li>Oil, grease and messes clean up easily</li>
	<li>
<a title="Garage Flooring Rolls and Tiles" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/GARAGE-FLOORING" target="_blank">Garage flooring</a> is thin. 1/8" or so. Garage Flooring is not impact resistant for weights/gym equipment.</li>
	<li>Garage flooring comes in rolls that are 7.5' - 10' wide</li>
	<li>Garage flooring is not porous and will not absorb oil, water, sweat, blood, grease, etc.</li>
</ul>
[caption id="attachment_113" align="alignnone" width="221"]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/garage_coin.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-113" alt="Vinyl Garage Flooring" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_garage_coin-300x300.jpg?9325338390910109507" width="221" height="221"></a> Garage Flooring is best suited for vehicular areas and work trailers.[/caption]
<strong>Rubber Flooring Characteristics:</strong>
<ul>
	<li>
<a title="Recycled Rubber Mats and Rolls" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/Rubber-Flooring" target="_blank">Recycled Rubber Flooring </a>materials are mostly black with color speckles (high color percentages are expensive and less common)</li>
	<li>Weight Room Flooring is made of - Rubber Flooring!</li>
	<li>Rubber flooring can be hard to clean dirt, dust, grease, oil, etc.</li>
	<li>Rubber flooring is resilient to impact and made for fitness areas with dumbbells, etc.</li>
	<li>There are many styles of varieties of rubber flooring, most affordable rubber floors are made of recycled materials.</li>
	<li>Rubber flooring is generally NOT a good choice for oily and greasy areas like mechanics shops, kitchens, and automotive areas unless there aren't significant messes to clean up.</li>
	<li>Recycled rubber flooring is semi-porous on the surface.</li>
	<li>Rubber flooring comes in 4' wide rolls or rubber tiles.</li>
</ul>
[caption id="attachment_114" align="alignnone" width="225"]<a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_color_wheel.jpg?16299706190874778259"><img class="size-full wp-image-114" alt="Rubber Floor Color Chart" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_color_wheel.jpg?16299706190874778259" width="225" height="225"></a> Rolled Rubber Flooring Basic Colors[/caption]
<strong>Recommended Garage Flooring Applications:</strong>
<ul>
	<li>Garage for vehicles and automotive work</li>
	<li>Car haulers/Trailers</li>
	<li>Motorcycle Trailers</li>
	<li>Tradeshows</li>
	<li>Excessively dirty/greasy areas</li>
	<li>Grease pits</li>
</ul>
<strong>Recommended Rubber Flooring Applications:</strong>
<ul>
	<li>Weight Rooms</li>
	<li>Home Gyms</li>
	<li>Workout Areas in Garages</li>
	<li>High Impact Areas</li>
	<li>Fitness Centers</li>
	<li>Cross Fit Gyms</li>
	<li>Under workout machines</li>
</ul>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/fake-rubber-flooring-sales-25-off-inc</id>
    <published>2013-04-04T17:05:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T18:27:41-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/fake-rubber-flooring-sales-25-off-inc"/>
    <title>Fake Rubber Flooring Sales 25% Off Inc</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong>Fake 25% off Rubber Flooring Sales Mislead Customers</strong>
What would you think of a company that says they are running a 25% off sale EVERY DAY of the year?
You might feel a little mislead right?  Do you wonder what other issues like quality and why sometimes the rubber shows up different than the samples you got?  I know the answer.  Do you?
Come on...you didn't think all rubber flooring was the same did you?
Here are some examples of the never ending fake sale banners. Let me guess...if you check their site...it's 25% off today but it ENDS Tuesday right???
[gallery]]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/how-to-properly-install-windscreen-and-fence-privacy-screen</id>
    <published>2013-02-15T01:17:21-06:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T18:26:35-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/how-to-properly-install-windscreen-and-fence-privacy-screen"/>
    <title>How to Properly Install Windscreen and Fence Privacy Screen</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong>Basic Installation Procedure:</strong>
The goal of a proper installation is to have a properly positioned, wrinkle free windscreen installation.  It's important to properly measure your fence and do a layout of the panels on paper so that you know where you are going to start and end each panel. DO NOT ATTEMPT INSTALLATION ON A WINDY DAY.
<strong>Equipment Needed:</strong> 7" - 50lb zip ties, hog ring pliers and hog rings (optional), ladder (depending on height of fence)
<ol>
	<li>Layout entire panel and start by securing the top beginning edge with a zip tie to the fence.  Secure the panel of windscreen at the proper height...typically, the bottom of the windscreen would be 6" off of the ground to allow air to pass and avoid damage from weed eaters.</li>
	<li>Secure the bottom starting edge with a zip ties as well; make sure the stating edge is straight. This helps keep the screen tight and wrinkle free.</li>
	<li>Use temporary S hooks to take vertical weight and load off the entire length of the screen..  Pull the slack out of each section.</li>
	<li>Secure the top edge of the screen with zip ties through ALL grommet holes, ensuring the screen is tight as you move down the length of the screen. Do NOT skip grommets.</li>
	<li>Go back and pull the vertical slack out of the windscreen vertically and attached the bottom grommets.</li>
	<li>If you want a more permanent installation; you can go back with a hog ring pliers and use steel hog rings to secure the windscreen.</li>
</ol>
[caption id="attachment_86" align="alignnone" width="407" caption="Example of Incorrect Installation"]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/bad_windscreen.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-86" title="bad_windscreen" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_bad_windscreen-300x225.jpg?3309837854928528214" alt="Installation Windscreen Incorrectly" width="407" height="305"></a>[/caption]
[caption id="attachment_88" align="alignnone" width="440" caption="Proper Installation of Windscreen will look great and last much longer."]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/windscreen_good1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-88" title="windscreen_good" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_windscreen_good1-300x146.jpg?8442210182757341600" alt="Proper Installation of Windscreen" width="440" height="214"></a>[/caption]]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/kodiak-sports-offers-legend-fitness-equipment</id>
    <published>2013-02-15T00:48:11-06:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T18:25:32-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/kodiak-sports-offers-legend-fitness-equipment"/>
    <title>Kodiak Sports offers Legend Fitness Equipment</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong>Kodiak now carriers Legend Fitness Equipment</strong>
Kodiak Sports has partnered with Legend Fitness to offer a full line of racks, squat racks, plate loaded stations, platforms, plate storage, body weight stations and more.
The equipment is an excellent complimentary line to Kodiak's <a title="Rubber Flooring" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/RUBBER-FLOORING">Rubber Flooring</a> and <a title="Artificial Turf" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/Artificial-Turf">Artificial Turf</a> used in speed and agility clinics.  Legend Fitness has an excellent reputation for it's pro series half rack and full racks with platforms.  Kodiak Sports is now capable of outfitting full collegiate, high school and commercial weight room facilities.
Pro Series Power Cage
[caption id="attachment_82" align="alignnone" width="300" caption="Legend Pro Series Power Cage with Platform"]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/legend.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-82" title="legend" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_legend-300x300.jpg?15842366229401729719" alt="Power Cage" width="300" height="300"></a>[/caption]
 
 ]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/windscreen-for-baseball-fields-and-tennis-courts</id>
    <published>2012-04-02T17:22:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T18:24:30-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/windscreen-for-baseball-fields-and-tennis-courts"/>
    <title>Windscreen for Baseball Fields and Tennis Courts</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<a title="Windscreen" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/BASEBALL-SOFTBALL/Windscreen" target="_blank">Windscreen</a> is used to enhance the look of a baseball field, tennis court, industrial or commercial lot, while blocking wind and unwanted on-lookers from viewing areas.  Windscreen can be used indoor and outdoor as a privacy barrier, or to prevent distractions in <a title="Batting Cages" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/" target="_blank">batting cages</a>.
Kodiak windscreen is super strong using a 6-ply windscreen construction at the hem, 4 plies of reinforced binding and 2 layers of windscreen.  The windscreen hems are 1.5" wide and are double sewn with polyester thread for long lasting performance in the sun and wind.
Kodiak offers a standard VCM (pvc coated polyester) windscreen in 5', 6' and 9' heights, while offering a super duty windscreen ArmorMesh (vinyl coated polyester) in 6' and 9' heights.
<strong>Key Features of Kodiak Windscreens:</strong>
<ul>
	<li>Brass Grommets that won't rust on windscreen</li>
	<li>Windscreen with 6X reinforced hems sewn with polyester thread</li>
	<li>Windscreen over 6' high has a center hem with extra grommets for additional strength</li>
	<li>Custom cut windscreen half moon or box shaped air vents available</li>
	<li>Custom windscreen printing available for logos, letters and numbers</li>
</ul>
<strong>Windscreen Photo Gallery:</strong>
[caption id="attachment_65" align="alignnone" width="398" caption="Windscreen Color Chart"]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/vcm_colors.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-65" title="vcm_colors" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_vcm_colors-300x99.jpg?15226150915972048234" alt="Windscreen Color Chart" width="398" height="131"></a>[/caption]
[caption id="attachment_64" align="alignnone" width="276" caption="Windscreen Box Shape Air Vent"]<a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_air_vent.jpg?10398566471169775678"><img class="size-full wp-image-64" title="air_vent" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_air_vent.jpg?10398566471169775678" alt="Windscreen Air Vent" width="276" height="182"></a>[/caption]
 ]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/everlock-interlocking-rubber-flooring-tiles-by-kodiak</id>
    <published>2012-03-29T00:07:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T18:23:27-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/everlock-interlocking-rubber-flooring-tiles-by-kodiak"/>
    <title>Everlock Interlocking Rubber Flooring Tiles by Kodiak</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong>3' x 3' Kodiak Everlock Rubber Tile Advantages</strong>
Kodiak 3' x 3' Everlock tiles are a commercial grade of rubber flooring tiles that are offered in 1/4", 3/8" and 1/2" Thick.  The <a title="Interlocking Rubber Flooring" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/RUBBER-FLOORING/Everlock-Rubber-Flooring-Tiles" target="_blank">interlocking rubber flooring </a>mats are CNC waterjet cut (precision computer controlled water cutting) for the tightest interlocking system possible.  The triangular design of the interlocking pattern is designed so that it pulls the tile together as the tiles interlock and fits separation.
The Kodiak Everlock rubber flooring tiles are made of the same material as the Kodiak <a title="Rubber Flooring for Weight Rooms" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/RUBBER-FLOORING/Rolled-Rubber-Flooring" target="_blank">Rolled Rubber Flooring</a> and is offered in the same full color line as the Commercial Grade Rolled Rubber Flooring.  The Everlock Tiles and the rolled rubber flooring come with a 5 year full wear warranty.  The rubber floor mats are also reversible to extend the life of the flooring even further.
<strong>Everlock Interlocking Rubber Tile Photo:</strong>
[caption id="attachment_59" align="alignnone" width="300" caption="The triangular shape of the interlocks helps keep the rubbber flooring tiles very tightly interlocked."]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/am_everlock_closeup.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-59" title="am_everlock_closeup" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_am_everlock_closeup-300x300.jpg?8498337157794687579" alt="Interlocking Rubber Flooring" width="300" height="300"></a>[/caption]
 ]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/artificial-turf-for-baseball-infields-and-baseball-fields</id>
    <published>2012-03-11T00:02:56-06:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T18:18:26-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/artificial-turf-for-baseball-infields-and-baseball-fields"/>
    <title>Artificial Turf for Baseball Infields and Baseball Fields</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong>Kodiak Sports Announces new Baseball Field Turf Model FL416</strong>
Kodiak Sports has announced the release of a new athletic field <a title="Synthetic Turf and Artificial Turf" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/Artificial-Turf" target="_blank">synthetic turf</a> for use on baseball infields that provides realistic play and reduced rubber infill fly out.
The new FL416 product is a heavy 50oz <a title="Artificial Turf" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/Artificial-Turf" target="_blank">artificial turf</a> with a thatch layer to provide reduced crumb rubber fly out and excellent ball roll.
[caption id="attachment_54" align="alignnone" width="300" caption="Side View of Artificial Turf for Kodiak Baseball Field"]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/fl_416_side.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-54" title="fl_416_side" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_fl_416_side-300x188.jpg?10330208086054707981" alt="Synthetic Turf" width="300" height="188"></a>[/caption]
Kodiak's synthetic <a title="Field Turf" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/Artificial-Turf" target="_blank">field turf</a> products are among the best in the nation; utilizing Tencate yarn (the world's best and largest producer of synthetic turf yarn).  Kodiak artificial turf products are the best in the world because of the quality of materials used in production and the care taken to produce a quality product from primary backing, tufting and a perfect coating process.
Kodiak Sports also offers installation of our artificial turf baseball infields.  Kodiak offers an upgrade in drainage base from the traditional stone/gravel compacted base to a polymer Ultra Base synthetic turf drain core system.  The Ultra Base system is still very close to the cost of a 100% stone base, but offers many advantages in playability and future field replacement costs.  With a Kodiak artificial turf infield; your baseball infield will never be rained out again
Artificial Turf Baseball Field with Kodiak FL416.
<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/ks_fl416.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-53" title="ks_fl416" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_ks_fl416-300x197.jpg?16875720752732671060" alt="Artificial Turf Baseball Field" width="300" height="197"></a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/3-types-of-baseball-backstop-and-wall-padding</id>
    <published>2012-02-27T22:53:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-08T13:13:31-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/3-types-of-baseball-backstop-and-wall-padding"/>
    <title>3 Types of Baseball Backstop and Wall Padding</title>
    <author>
      <name>Amy White</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>Baseball and Softball Backstop and Wall Padding</strong></p>
<p>Baseball <a title="Wall Padding" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/BASEBALL-SOFTBALL/Backstop-Padding" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wall padding </a>is commonly used on baseball chain link fences, brick walls, backstops, and other areas to cushion the impact of the baseball or protect the athlete from injury. <a title="Softball and Baseball Backstop Padding" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/BASEBALL-SOFTBALL/Backstop-Padding" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Backstop padding</a> is typically 2" thick in a standard pad; however may be ordered in 3" or 4" thick pads as well. </p>
<p>A good quality backstop pad is comprised of a firm weather proof foam; typically ILD 100 foam.  This quality foam ensures the padding will not rot or degrade in an outdoor or moist environment.</p>
<p><strong>Backstop Padding Mounting Options:</strong> There are 3 types of mounting options in standard baseball backstop padding and sports wall padding.</p>
<p><strong>Grommet Mounted Pads:</strong> Grommets are placed on the top and bottom line of the wall padding; and are mounted to the chain link fence with zip ties or solid wall with screws and washers. Grommetted pads are the weakest form of mounting, however it is the most economical.</p>
<p><strong>Wood Backed with Nailer Lips:</strong> The next level of wall pad mounting is a wood back with nailer lip.  A weather treated wood is used and the wood extends 1" above and below the padding to aid in the mounting of the padding to the solid wall.  Typically wood back padding is used on brick or concrete walls; it is not as popular for use on chain link fencing; however it is not wrong or unreasonable to use a wood back sports pad on a chain link fence. The nailer lip is typically wrapped in vinyl to match the pad color; and you place the anchor screws through the nailer lip to mount the pad.</p>
<p><strong>Z-Clip Sports Padding with Wood Backing:</strong> The professional method of mounting wall padding and baseball backstop padding is to use a wood backed pad with z-clip to fasten the pad to the wall.  The wood backing of equal size to the backstop padding; and the z-clip rails are a mounted to the wood backing and the concrete or brick wall.  The pads are hung from the z-clips. Z-clips give you the advantage of removable pads and a completely hidden mounting system.</p>
<p><a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_zclip.jpg?8000053371007106862"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-50" title="zclip" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_zclip.jpg?8000053371007106862" alt="Wall Padding with Z-Clips" width="200" height="200"></a></p>
<p>Call Kodiak Sports Today at 877-401-2298 for your <a href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/collections/sports-padding/products/backstop-padding" title="Backstop padding">Baseball and Softball Backstop and Wall Padding!</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/rolled-rubber-weight-room-flooring</id>
    <published>2012-02-21T22:17:15-06:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T18:10:31-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/rolled-rubber-weight-room-flooring"/>
    <title>Rolled Rubber Weight Room Flooring</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong>Rolled Rubber Flooring Basic Product Overview:</strong>
<a title="Recycled Rubber Flooring" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/RUBBER-FLOORING" target="_blank">Recycled rubber flooring</a> is the most popular form of recycled rubber flooring used in weight rooms for commercial fitness centers, franchises, schools and locker rooms.  Good quality rolled rubber flooring has several advantages over interlocking rubber flooring tiles and other forms of flooring materials.
There are many grades of <a title="Rubber Floooring" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/RUBBER-FLOORING/Rolled-Rubber-Flooring" target="_blank">rolled rubber flooring</a>; as density, binders, deodorizing agents and other ingredients vary in quantity and proportion to create a cheap or quality floor.  The differences in quality make it important to choose a good quality floor with a good reputation.  Kodiak flooring is used by the most discriminating universities and professional sports teams in the United States.  Our client list is a who's who of professional organizations and high end weight rooms.
Kodiak rolled rubber flooring is easy to clean in a commercial grade product.  Kodiak flooring is a high density commercial grade product.  The high density ensures fewer surface pores and a smoother and longer lasting surface.  Kodiak rolled rubber flooring also has no odor; which is very important to customers and commercial fitness centers.
<strong>Rolled Rubber Flooring Highlights:</strong>
<ul>
	<li>Easy to clean</li>
	<li>No Rubber Odor</li>
	<li>Seamless Installation when glued down</li>
	<li>Affordable and Economical</li>
	<li>Good Life Cycle Maintenance</li>
	<li>Kodiak 5 Year Wear Warranty</li>
</ul>
 
 ]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/batting-cage-construction-and-installation</id>
    <published>2012-02-16T22:34:40-06:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T18:05:03-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/batting-cage-construction-and-installation"/>
    <title>Batting Cage Construction and Installation</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[Matt Garrabrants, Owner and Founder of Kodiak Sports has been building custom sports facilities and batting cages for over 15 years. Over the last 15 years Kodiak Sports has performed installations all over the United States for MLB clubs, parks, spring training complexes and private individuals.  Matt Garrabrants is one of the foremost experts and sought after batting cages experts in the world; and for special jobs will travel internationally for installations if the job is interesting and a good fit.
Kodiak Sports specializes in helping retired athletes, business owners, cities, parks and recreation divisions and professional baseball clubs outfit their indoor and outdoor batting cages and baseball facilities.
<strong>Batting Cage Installation Services</strong>:
<ul>
	<li><a title="Batting Cage Installation and Construction" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/installation-services" target="_blank">Batting Cage Layout and Design Consultation</a></li>
	<li><a title="Artificial and Synthetic Turf Fields" href="http://www.syntheticturf.com" target="_blank">Artificial Sports Turf</a></li>
	<li><a title="Rubber Flooring" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/Rubber-Flooring" target="_blank">Rubber Flooring</a></li>
	<li>Custom <a title="Batting Cage Nets" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/BASEBALL-SOFTBALL/Batting-Cage-Nets" target="_blank">Batting Cage Nets</a>
</li>
	<li><a title="Baseball Turf Hitting Mats" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/Artificial-Turf/Synthetic-Turf-Hitting-Mats" target="_blank">Turf Hitting Mats</a></li>
	<li><a title="L-Screens" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/BASEBALL-SOFTBALL/Pitching-LScreens" target="_blank">Pitching L-Screens</a></li>
	<li>Ball Buckets</li>
	<li>Sock Nets</li>
	<li>Baseballs</li>
	<li>Video <a title="Pitching Machines" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/BASEBALL-SOFTBALL/Pitching-Machines" target="_blank">Pitching Machines</a>
</li>
	<li><a title="Commercial Iron Mike Pitching Machines" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/BASEBALL-SOFTBALL/Iron-Mike-Pitching-Machines" target="_blank">Iron Mike Pitching Machines</a></li>
	<li>Retractable Velcro Turf Fields</li>
</ul>
Kodiak Sports manufacturers sports turf, rubber flooring, L-Screens, Baseballs, Batting Cage Nets, and other equipment to supply your commercial batting cage.  Manufacturing our own equipment ensures quality control and cost control management; guaranteeing you the best price.]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/batting-cage-turf-educational-overview</id>
    <published>2012-02-16T10:55:13-06:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T18:00:48-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/batting-cage-turf-educational-overview"/>
    <title>Batting Cage Turf Educational Overview</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong>Batting Cage Turf Educational Overview:</strong>
Purchasing a <a title="Batting Cage Nets" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/BASEBALL-SOFTBALL/Batting-Cage-Nets" target="_blank">batting cage</a> turf begins with educating yourself on some of the basics of sports turf.  If you don't understand what you are buying, how can you be sure you are getting a good deal?  Kodiak gets calls everyday from someone thinking they found some wonderful turf for $1.00/sq. ft. or less...when in fact, they just don't understand what they are purchasing.  In the world of <a title="Batting Cage Turf" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/Artificial-Turf/Batting-Cage-Turf">batting cage turf</a>, you always get what you pay for, no exceptions.
<strong>Primary Backings:</strong>
The primary backing could be considered the skeleton of the sports turf.  It is the black poly backing in which the actual turf fibers get sewn through...much like the primary backing of a carpet.  Kodiak primary backings are always a heavy duty 22oz primary backing; but on cheaper turfs; some companies use a lighter backing, saving them money and costing you strength, durability, and quality in your <a title="Sports Turf for Batting Cages" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/Artificial-Turf">sports turf</a>.
<strong>Artificial Turf Face Fiber Overview:</strong>
The face fiber is the biggest variable in the cost and quality of a sports turf.  There are many kinds and styles of fibers; and to compound the problem, there are 1st, 2nd and 3rd grade of yarns.  Extruding yarn is a difficult process to perform properly and consistently; so when the yarn mfg. makes a mistake, they sell that yarn at a discount.  Sometimes the discounts are color related and not performance related; other mistakes in texturization cause premature field failure.  So next time you think you are buying something 1/2 price, you'll know why...it was a 2nd, 3rd or even 4th quality yarn.
<strong>Artificial Turf Face Fiber Types:</strong>
There are 3 basic yarn/face fiber types.  Polypropylene (PolyP), Polyethylene(PolyE) and Nylon.
<strong>PolyP</strong> - Olefin/PolyP is used in lower grade carpets and lower grade astro turf/foam padded sports turfs.  That does NOT mean that there aren't great turfs made of PolyP fibers.  What it means is that if you compare a 36oz PolyP to a 36oz Nylon turf, the Nylon will outlast the PolyP.  There are also different grades of yarn, multi-filament and monofilament yarns.  Monofilament are higher grade and will last split/wear as easily.
<strong>PolyE</strong> - PolyE yarns are used on outdoor athletic fields due to their softness.  They do not perform well without rubber infill, as they have very little rigidity and durability without rubber.  It is possible to texturize/spring set a PolyE yarn and use it in a foam padded turf; however the face weight needs to be a minimum of 40oz to have any lasting durability.
<strong>Nylon</strong> - Nylon is the toughest/longest lasting and most expensive fiber used in sports turfs.  Nylon has high abrasion resistance, excellent UV characteristics and typically is only extruded in monofilament yarns.  Nylon is also mixed in some higher end turfs with PolyE to provide durability in a turf that is also soft.  See the Kodiak Arena Turfs line for hybrid turfs mixing nylon and PolyE.
<strong>Texturized (Spring Set) or Straight Fibers:</strong>
<strong>Texturized Yarns:</strong> Texturization is a process in which heat, steam, tension, and other methods are used to create a "jerry curl" or spring set in the yarn. Spring set yarns are more durable and resist crushing/traffic patterns because they spring back into place when used.  Spring set yarns will outlast a straight fiber yarn in a similar face weight product by 40-60%.
<strong>Straight Yarns:</strong> If a yarn is not texturized, the fibers are basically straight.  Straight yarns are cheaper and do not resist traffic patterns well.  They are often marketed by companies as a good product, but will not wear well.  The cost different in a straight fiber yarn on a 36oz poly product may be as much as 50 cents per sq. ft. !  So if you are shopping for 36oz poly turfs, you better know what you are buying, or you may get stuck with a low grade straight fiber turf.
<strong>Buying a Turf:</strong>
Kodiak is the nationwide leader in indoor sports facility turf and rubber flooring.  Don't be fooled by cheap products and fake low prices; buy a <a title="Sports Turf for Soccer and Arena Football" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com">sports turf</a> from Kodiak knowing you purchased a quality product.
Kodiak's <a title="Artificial Sports and Batting Cage Turf" href="http://www.syntheticturf.com">artificial sports turfs</a> are made from USA yarn that is lead free.  Kodiak Sports produces approx. 28 types of sports turf; offering various grades and qualities to meet your business needs and budget.
 
 ]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/fort-benning-ga-cross-fit-turf</id>
    <published>2012-02-15T11:27:21-06:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T17:58:43-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/fort-benning-ga-cross-fit-turf"/>
    <title>Fort Benning, GA Cross Fit Turf</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong>Cross Fit Turf and Rubber Flooring at Ft. Benning, GA</strong>
Kodiak is the nationwide leader in building custom sports facilities, cross fit floors and speed/agility/rehab rooms for the military and private baseball batting cage facilities.
Kodiak can supply our 52oz Steel Spike Proof Nylon Sports Turf with 5mm foam cushion in nearly any color to give your <a title="Cross Fit Flooring" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com">cross fit</a> facility a cutting edge look and feel.  Our <a title="Artificial Astro Turf" href="http://www.syntheticturf.com">astro turf</a> is so durable you can drag anchor chains, perform tire flips, sled pulls, and more!  Kodiak 52N turf is made of 100% monofilament nylon; making it the most durable turf on the market today.  We also have lower grades of turf to meet any sports facilities budget requirements.  Turf prices range from $1.00 - $5/per sq. ft.
Kodiak performs nationwide <a title="Rubber Flooring Installation" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com">flooring installations</a> for rubber flooring, batting cage turf, synthetic turf, interlocking rubber tiles and artificial turf fields.
[caption id="attachment_35" align="alignnone" width="300" caption="Black Kodiak Sports Artificial Turf For Crossfit at Ft. Benning, GA"]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/blackturf.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-35" title="Black Astro Turf" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_blackturf-300x225.jpg?10050441115731438468" alt="Astro Turf for Cross Fit and Plyometric Training" width="300" height="225"></a>[/caption]]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/what-makes-a-good-artificial-turf-halo</id>
    <published>2012-02-13T16:46:32-06:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T17:53:55-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.kodiaksports.com/blogs/kodiak-sports-blog/what-makes-a-good-artificial-turf-halo"/>
    <title>What makes a good Artificial Turf Halo?</title>
    <author>
      <name>1</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[Kodiak Sports artificial<a title="Artificial Turf Halo" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/Artificial-Turf/Baseball-Turf-Halos"> turf halos </a>are made of 52oz Steel Spike Proof Nylon sports turf.
Kodiak <a title="Artificial Sports Turf" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com/Artificial-Turf">Artificial Turf</a> Halos come with a 5mm reinforced foam pad for additional cushioning, life and weight.  The turf halos are sold with and without wings and are sold in 2 standard sizes.  5' and 10' Thick.  We can also do custom halo sizes to fit your pitching mound or smaller/larger diameter field areas.
Nylon is the toughest yarn in the sports turf industry.  Nylon <a title="Synthetic Sports Turf" href="http://www.kodiaksports.com">sports turf</a> has higher melting points and abrasion strength characteristics than polyP or polyE yarns.  Nylon is also a more expensive yarn, therefore producing a slightly higher priced product; but one that is superior in quality under the heavy uses of an outdoor athletic field.
<strong>Kodiak Turf Halo Highlights:</strong>
<ul>
	<li>52oz Spike Proof Nylon (competitors are 36oz poly)</li>
	<li>5mm Reinforced Action Backed Foam Pad</li>
	<li>Logos and Letters in Waterjet Cut into the Turf Halo (not painted on</li>
</ul>
[caption id="attachment_29" align="alignnone" width="300" caption="Turf Halo With Wings, 2 Color Inlaid Lettering"]<a href="http://blog.kodiaksports.com/assets/kodiak_halo.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-29" title="Kodiak Turf Halo" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1150/3206/files/blog_kodiak_halo-300x226.jpg?15408909287153909644" alt="Artificial Turf Halo" width="300" height="226"></a>[/caption]]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
